Terrific.
[tapping]
- [tinkling]
- [liquid pouring]
[whisking]
[birdsong]
Hi, buddy.
Good morning.
[piano version
of "Enough for You" playing]
[laughs] Yeah! Oh!
[girl] ♪ I wore makeup when we dated ♪
♪ 'Cause I thought you'd like me more ♪
♪ If I looked like the other prom queens ♪
♪ I know that you loved before ♪
♪ Tried so hard to be
Everything that you liked ♪
♪ Just for you to say
You're not the compliment type ♪
♪ And I knew how you took your coffee ♪
♪ And your favorite songs by heart ♪
♪ I read all of your self-help books ♪
♪ So you'd think that I was smart ♪
♪ Stupid, emotional, obsessive little me ♪
♪ I knew from the start-- ♪
- [sizzling]
- Ow! Ow! Ugh, you idiot!
- [mother] Sophie?
- [man] You all right?
I'm fine!
[whimpers] Oh! No.
And you feel good
about your audition song?
Well, I did
until I burned myself practicing.
Aw. Just means
you're losing yourself in it. It's good.
Maybe just don't sing
and curl at the same time.
- Okay.
- [chuckles] That looks good.
- Does it?
- Mmm. Kind of.
All right.
Ugh. Mallory's gonna get Jenna.
Everybody knows that.
And Jenna is…
The main waitress in Waitress.
It's like playing Annie in Annie.
Oh.
I can maybe get Dawn.
She's the funny friend.
I just want to be good.
Oh, honey, you will be.
[phone ringing]
Why is Dad calling me?
- [mother] I don't know.
- Hello?
Please don't… don't lick your brother.
- [Sophie] Ugh. Butt-dial.
- [dad] Ethan…
- Should we do the thing?
- Your brother's licking the floor.
- This is an issue for both of you.
- [child talking]
It's so… so dirty.
Uh, Sophie, thank you so much
for showing me those butterfly tattoos
that go all the way
from your neck down your back.
They're stunning.
Yes. Thank you
for giving me permission to do that
and telling me to not tell Dad.
Yes, of course, because we all know
that your father
doesn't believe in women's rights.
- Mm-hmm.
- Go lick a vegetable.
- He can't hear us.
- No, that was crazy.
- [laughs]
- Ted! Your phone!
[Ted] Again?
- Yes!
- I can't.
Can I have a snack?
A snack? You just had breakfast.
- [Sophie] Oh, it's true.
- [mother] No, but seriously?
[Ted] Hey, did you do teeth?
- I did not.
- I brushed mine and Ethan's.
- His tongue had white dots on it.
- [Ethan] So does yours.
Uh… your brothers ate
all the bagels and the eggs.
But I got you a banana.
I know, a banana is not a bagel.
- Banana's perfect, Dad.
- Thank you.
Who wants a ride?
- Come on, boys.
- [Ethan] I want a ride.
- I'll be back for you later.
- Okay.
We're gonna be good.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
- I love you.
- [Ethan] Don't wanna get stuck in traffic.
- Be nice to your brother. Leave him alone.
You are beautiful and talented.
- Oh, jeez.
- And ready.
- [laughs] Thank you.
- [car horn beeps]
- Carolyn's waiting. I should go.
- Yes.
Driving lessons soon, I promise.
Am I allowed to say "good luck"?
Just say "break a leg."
But I would be so sad
if you broke your leg.
- You'll get over it.
- [chuckles]
- I love you.
- Bye-bye.
["Young Blood"
by The Naked and Famous playing]
- Oh.
- What?
Did you bring a hat?
You can audition in a hat.
I'm telling people it's a hickey,
and you're going along with it.
- On your face?
- Yes.
Oh, shut up. Just drive.
Dude, it's…
♪ The bittersweet between my teeth ♪
♪ Trying to find the in-betweens ♪
♪ Fall back in love eventually ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah… ♪
- Good morning, Frank.
- Morning, boss.
- [Ted] Hey, guys. Good morning.
- Hi.
- Good morning.
- [man] Thank you.
- Lenny, how's the kale wrap comin'?
- Oh, they're comin', they're comin'.
They should be on a bagel.
You're not understanding this, okay?
People want healthy.
All right? They wanna eat the wrap
and they wanna still be hungry.
But it's better on a bagel.
We still have bagels.
It's an option, Lenny.
Ooh, hey. I gotta take off early.
I'm bringing Lizzie someplace, okay?
Ooh, afternoon delight?
- [entry bell jangles]
- [chuckles]
Mmm!
Mmm. Ugh!
[spits]
[sighs]
[woman] And just make sure
you get through chapter six
so you're ready
for Wednesday's discussion, okay?
[school bell rings]
[teacher] All right, that's it.
And don't forget the quiz is next week.
♪ Mi, ma, mo, moo ♪
Nice and short. Ah!
- [all] ♪ Mi, me, ma, mo, moo ♪
- Relax your jaw.
- [teacher] Tuh!
- ♪ Ti, te, ta, toe, too ♪
- [teacher] Sh!
- ♪ Shi, shay, sha, sho, shoo ♪
- [teacher] Bh!
- [all] ♪ Bi, bay, bah, bo, boo ♪
- Shpluh!
- [all sing fast] ♪ Spli, splay, splah! ♪
- [teacher] Nice.
- We're ready.
- [laughter and cheering]
Shake it out, shake it out.
Gimme a drumroll.
Let's welcome to the room
your favorite teacher next to me,
your director for this production,
Ms. Parker!
[cheering]
Thank you!
Thank you very much, Mr. Stewart.
- Okay, people, let's do this!
- [cheering]
[exuberantly]
♪ I'll do such things to ease your pain ♪
♪ Free your mind
And you won't feel ashamed ♪
♪ Shucks, for me there is no other ♪
♪ You're the only shoe that fits ♪
♪ I can't imagine I'll grow out of it ♪
- ♪ Damn, I wish I was your lover… ♪
- Relax, you're gonna kill it.
Singing in front of everybody is so scary.
You're supposed to picture
everyone in their underwear.
♪ Damn, I wish I was your lover ♪
Actually, don't.
♪ Hanging around this jungle ♪
- [Carolyn] Except maybe Jack.
- Stop it.
♪ To change, ah! ♪
- [applause]
- [Ms. Parker] Thank you, Trista!
- [boy 1] Yeah!
- Really looked like you were havin' fun.
Thank you, Ms. Parker.
[Ms. Parker] Mallory?
- Crush it, Mallory.
- Sweet Sophie!
Hello.
[Mr. Stewart] Okay.
♪ Gimme, gimme ♪
- Forty-three.
- [girl 1] Go, Mal!
- [boy 2] You got this, Mal!
- [boy 3] Go!
- [girls] Whoo!
- [piano playing "Gimme Gimme"]
[Mallory] ♪ Gimme, gimme ♪
♪ That thing called love ♪
♪ I want it ♪
♪ Gimme, gimme ♪
♪ That thing called love ♪
♪ I need it… ♪
How big of an orgasm do you think
she's gonna have when she gets Jenna?
Stop. Don't be mean.
I'm not being mean!
A big orgasm is so nice.
♪ …that thing called love ♪
♪ Gimme, gimme… ♪
- Oh, think she just had one.
- ♪ That thing called love ♪
So, for Jenna, I'd like to call back
Hannah Williams and Mallory Sinclair.
Of course.
- For Dr. Pomatter, Jack Davis, TJ Everett.
- Yes!
[girl 2] Yeah, TJ!
For Dawn, Rebecca Lewis
and Sophie Birenbaum.
- [gasps]
- [Ms. Parker] For Becky…
[car engine starts]
[PA chimes]
[woman on PA]
Dr. Lambert to imaging, please.
Dr. Lambert to imaging.
It's nice your husband came with you.
Oh. Yeah.
I haven't told mine yet.
Um…
- Do you wanna practice on mine?
- [laughs]
[woman] Elizabeth Birenbaum?
[PA chimes]
Dr. Vaughan, please come…
[Elizabeth sighs]
Dr. Vaughan…
Good luck.
Thanks.
[footsteps approaching]
[man] Elizabeth. Ted.
Jenna, our lead.
A waitress in a small-town diner
and incredible baker of pies.
Before she died,
her mom taught Jenna how to bake.
And now, Jenna is pregnant herself,
but she's in a bad relationship
with the baby's father.
- [whispers] I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
- Nervous pee?
Always.
♪ What if when he sees me
I like him and he knows it? ♪
♪ What if he opens up a door
And I can't close it? ♪
- ♪ What happens… ♪
- [phone buzzing]
- Hi, Dad.
- [Ted] My God.
Ugh. Can you please stop butt-dialing me?
- [Elizabeth] When do we tell them?
- [Ted] I don't know.
[Elizabeth sighs]
I can't believe this.
I just… I can't believe this.
- [Ted] I know.
- [Elizabeth] I can't…
- [sniffles]
- [Ted] I know.
[hangs up]
[boy] ♪ To know you want more… ♪
[whispering] That was a long pee.
Sure it was a pee?
- Can you please take me home?
- Now? We haven't gone up yet.
- Uh, it's fine. I'll just walk.
- You've gotta learn to drive.
It's not my parents' biggest priority
right now.
[cheering and applause]
[boy 1] Go, TJ!
Thank you very much, TJ.
[whispers] Soph, what's going on?
[Ms. Parker] Sophie Birenbaum?
Sophie.
Just a second.
At Stage Door Manor, they taught us
this breathing technique. Ready?
In, two, three.
[whispers] Hold, two, three, four.
- [exhales shakily]
- Two, three, four.
You got this.
[mouths]
[Mallory] That's it.
- [TJ] Hey. Was it good? Yeah?
- [chuckles] It was good.
[seat hinges grinding loudly]
Sorry.
♪ What if when he sees me
I like him and he knows it? ♪
♪ What if he opens up a door
And I can't close it? ♪
[sniffles]
♪ What happens then? ♪
♪ If when he holds me ♪
♪ My heart is set in motion ♪
♪ I'm not prepared for that ♪
♪I'm scared of breaking open ♪
♪ But still I can't help from hoping ♪
♪ To find someone to talk to ♪
♪ Who likes the way I am ♪
♪ Someone who, when he sees me ♪
[breathing shakily]
♪ Wants to again ♪
[applause]
Hi!
- [Ted] How'd the audition go?
- [brother] I want him not to run!
- [Sophie] It was fine.
- My turn! Me first!
- [Sophie] Get off. Stop.
- Boys, boys, boys.
- [Elizabeth] Boys, be gentle.
- [Ted] Hey. I got ya. I got ya.
There must be more to the story
than "fine," right?
I don't know.
[Ted] Hey, guys, uh… why don't we
go to the living room for a minute?
Mom and I need
to talk to you about something.
Come on, Soph.
- ["A Good Thing" by Claud playing]
- [phone ringing]
♪ Don't try and fix it if-- ♪
- [turns music off]
- [phone chimes]
It came back.
[Carolyn] No.
Yeah. They said she's gonna fight it.
To figure out a treatment plan, but…
Right. And they figured it out
last time, so…
I don't want anyone to know.
I totally get that.
I'm here for you. Okay?
Always.
They didn't even tell me
they were going in today.
She didn't even seem like she…
I'm gonna go.
- Soph…
- [disconnection tone beeps]
[sobbing]
[poignant music playing]
[Trista] The cast list is out!
Attention all thespians,
the cast list is out!
- Sorry!
- [girl 1] Trista!
Are you ready?
- Mmm… I don't know.
- [lockers open and slam]
- You don't have to do it, you know.
- Uh, what?
I'm not trying to be rude.
It's just, you're a sophomore.
I mean… have you ever even done
a summer intensive?
Wait, I'm so confused. Did I get Dawn?
I'm gonna get in there.
I got Dawn.
Mal… Mal, let's just…
[Carolyn] Um… Sophie?
[exciting music playing]
[girl 2] Here she is.
[Ted] Guys, there you go.
[entry bell jangles]
I got the lead.
Oh, hey. What's up?
Annie? You got Annie?
- [Ted] What do you mean, Annie?
- Yeah.
- No, she got the… the lead. Jenna.
- You got the lead lead?
The… the lead, the Annie?
- Yes.
- Whoa!
- [Ted] Congratulations.
- [Lenny] Mazel tov, Sophie.
- [Elizabeth] Ooh!
- [Ted] My baby got the lead in the play!
- Oh, we have to go eat and celebrate.
- [Ted] Yeah, yeah. We'll go out.
♪ The sun'll come out tomorrow ♪
- ♪ Bet your bottom dollar that tomorrow ♪
- [Ted joins in] ♪Tomorrow ♪
♪ There'll be sun ♪
♪ Tomorrow, tomorr-- ♪
Musicals are stupid.
Oh, come on, buddy. Don't say stupid.
Why do they sing? Just be talking.
Because music can make you feel things
that are bigger than just talking, Caleb.
It shows people going through stuff,
like when things are hard or fun.
You can see how
other people go through that too.
What's the stuff in your one?
Well, I play Jenna,
who is pregnant and bakes pies.
And her husband…
isn't nice like Dad, and then
she falls in love with her gynecologist.
- Her what?
- [Ted] Wait, hold on.
Wasn't last year, like, fairy tales?
- It was Sondheim.
- [woman] Elizabeth.
Hi, Shelly.
I just heard.
I'm so sorry.
Um…
We are actually celebrating Sophie
tonight. She got the lead in her play.
And you brought her to Lee's.
You're such a good mom.
You're gonna beat it just like last time.
I said to June Nizio,
"I can't believe out of everyone…"
[Sophie] Mom, maybe
I shouldn't do the show.
- [Elizabeth] Of course you should.
- [boys barking]
[Elizabeth] I love watching you perform.
I will never forget your first solo.
- The second-grade concert.
- [Ted] The back seat.
- ♪ You just gotta ignite the light ♪
- Oh, please don't do this.
- ♪ And let it shine ♪
- [Sophie laughs]
- ♪ Just own the night ♪
- [Sophie] Mom!
- Stop!
- ♪ Like the 4th of July ♪
Okay, enough.
♪ 'Cause baby, you're a fire… ♪ [chuckles]
- You were so good, though.
- Thank you.
- I cried so much. Oh.
- [gentle music playing]
Get ready to weep.
Okay, I'm gonna put it in the calendar.
What are the exact dates?
- Uh, May 15th and 16th.
- Okay.
15th… Oh.
It's just a couple of weeks
before the beach rental.
This is gonna be great.
We're still going?
To the Crane House?
Honey, yeah.
Of course we're going to the beach.
- We always go to the beach.
- [car starts]
[boys barking and growling]
[Ted] Please get in.
They've been doing this the whole time.
- [Elizabeth] I'm sorry.
- What are you doing out here?
- [Elizabeth] Talking.
- [Sophie] Yeah.
- [pop music playing]
- [girl] Yeah, sounds nice.
[laughter]
[boy] Nice highlighting.
[Sophie] Oh, um… it's just normal.
- Here. You can have it.
- But you're not done.
Uh… No, I like to take highlighter breaks
so I don't get carpal tunnel syndrome.
Have you heard of carpal tunnel?
It… it affects your ligaments.
Sophie, right?
Uh, that is indeed my name.
I'm Jack. I'm playing Dr. Pomatter.
Yeah. We're gonna do
a lot of fun stuff together
onstage.
Oh.
[door opens]
[Ms. Parker] Hello, thespians!
Let's rehearse.
Can you feel my hand and how sweaty it is?
Yeah. Hmm.
It's slimy, it's clammy, it's oddly hot.
- All the things you don't want it to be.
- Aw, thank you.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
[group repeating] One, two, three, four,
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven!
One, two, three, four.
One, two, three. One, two, three.
One, two. One, two. One, two, one.
One! One! One! One! One!
[all shout, one at a time] Wah! Wah! Wah!
Wah! Wah! Wah! Wah! Wah! Wah! Wah! Wah!
[clapping]
[chanting rhythmically]
- [girl 1] Cherry!
- [Sophie] Oi!
- [girl 1] Bufala!
- [Sophie] Cherry!
- [girl 1] Orange.
- [Mallory] Oi!
- [girl 1] Bufala.
- [Mallory] Apple.
- [girl 1] Apple.
- [boy 1] Oi!
- [girl 1] Bufala.
- [Sophie] Pineapple.
- [girl 1] Pineapple.
- [Mr. Stewart] Oi!
[girl 1] Bufala.
- Passion fruit! Passion fruit!
- [all] Oi, oi, oi! Oh!
Hi, I'm Dr. Pomatter.
I just moved here from Connecticut,
and I'm a gynecologist.
[Southern accent] Hi, my name's Jebba…
I… I mean, Jenna.
- And, um, my baby's got a belly in it.
- [group giggling and whispering]
[Southern accent] My name's Dawn,
and my baby certainly
does not have a belly in it!
[laughter]
And my heart belongs
to the History Channel.
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh!
[exaggeratedly] I'm old Joe, the diner
owner, and my body's deterioratin'.
[laughter]
I play ensemble-slash-pie shop
customer number three,
and you don't want to go in my basement.
- [giggles]
- Huh?
[keys jangle]
Who's ready for a driving lesson?
Oh, no! What's wrong?
- Okay. No driving lesson?
- [door slams]
[car door alarm pinging]
What happened?
Everyone's accent sounds so good,
and I sound…
ugh, like a cartoon rooster.
Mom, it's not funny.
Sorry.
Maybe Ms. Parker made a mistake.
You know what?
I think I have an idea.
[starts engine]
- Mom, where are we even going?
- Hmm… Mmm!
[clears throat]
[Southern accent] Uh, excuse me, Angel.
Ahem. My daughter and I
are visitin' from Georgia,
and we're lookin' to buy
some bathin' suits.
Why don't you tell the nice lady
what kind of suit you want?
No, it's… it's fine.
Go ahead.
Tell her what kind of suit you fancy.
Um…
[Southern accent] Somethin', uh… sparkly.
Sparkly.
And what else?
With ruffles.
- Ruffles.
- Mm-hmm.
We don't really have that.
Well, y'all should.
My daughter is Miss Savannah,
and y'all just lost her business.
- Bless your heart.
- [giggles]
["Tiny Moves" by Bleachers playing]
- [Elizabeth] Ooh.
- [Sophie] Oh.
This chair is just much too firm
for my lil' bottom.
And this one's just too tiny
for my big 'un.
- [normally] Honey, you have the best butt.
- Mom, don't do that.
[Southern accent] Oh!
It spins!
Fancy!
- [chairs rumbling]
- [both giggling]
♪ Whoa, oh, oh! ♪
♪ Watchin' it all come down ♪
♪ Watch it go round and round… ♪
[Southern accent] I'll have ten
of your finest buttermilk biscuits
and a gallon of sweet tea.
This is a pizza place.
♪ On the edge again, on the edge again… ♪
- [Elizabeth laughing] Oh!
- [Sophie] Hey!
[Elizabeth] "Now remember what I said."
"Don't you go lovin' that baby
more than me."
"I don't love you anymore, Earl.
I haven't in a very long time."
What?
Ms. Parker didn't make a mistake.
[sighs]
Ahem. "That's not funny, Jenna."
[Sophie] ♪ She is messy ♪
- ♪ But she's kind ♪
- [mouthing]
♪ She is lonely most of the time ♪
- Okay, uh, let's pause.
- [piano stops]
- [sighs]
- [Ms. Parker] Um…
What are you feeling right now?
Uh, like I need a lot more practice.
Well, that's Sophie. You're Jenna.
Jenna,
everything in her life
has built to this moment right now.
Yeah, I know. I just…
I really want to get the notes right.
Forget about the notes, all right?
I want you to mess up.
That's how you get to the good stuff.
There's so much going on
in your life right now.
- What are you talking about?
- You're gonna have a baby, Jenna.
Right.
[Ms. Parker] Right. So put it in the song.
- Hmm?
- Right.
[Ms. Parker] Um, let's take it from…
["Eventually" by Tame Impala
playing on speakers]
[Carolyn] Another thing about Erin…
You okay?
Yeah.
Are you sure? Do you wanna, like…
No, no, no. Sorry. What were you saying?
Um…
Erin. She invited me
to this protest the other day,
and instead, I just sat in the auditorium
and did nothing for three hours.
You mean when we blocked the opening?
- I'm literally gonna be in the shadows.
- You look so cool.
- I mean, I'm excited for you.
- I'm excited for both of us.
I have one line, Sophie.
And your solo in "Club Knocked Up."
Come on, it's sounding so good. Belt it.
♪ Knock knock ♪
Nailed it.
- [Caleb] I'll get there first.
- [Ethan] I will.
[Ted] Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Please, no running. Stop, don't move.
Bring these to your friend Jeremy
and his dad.
- Some of that.
- [Elizabeth] Hey.
You really have to figure out
those driving lessons.
Otherwise, you're gonna go off to college,
and then you're gonna move
to New York and become a star,
and then you'll be one of those
New Yorkers who never learned to drive.
- I'll hire a hot chauffeur.
- [laughs]
- [Ethan] No, Jeremy, stop!
- [woman] Just…
- [Ethan] Jeremy, stop!
- What was that?
- [Caleb] Gimme the pickle.
- [Ethan] I want that bagel!
Okay, but what about when you fall in love
with your hot chauffeur
and get married and have kids
and then you have to drive them to school?
Why can't he drive them?
Because you will be better at it
because I taught you how to drive.
Mmm.
Women's rights.
Fine, teach me to drive.
Okay. Tomorrow, after school?
[Sophie] Uh, let me see.
- Ugh. Shoot. Rehearsal.
- [Ted] You wanna wear the shoes?
- You can't act like that. Come on.
- [Caleb] I'm telling Mom.
[Elizabeth] Ugh, what happened?
Ethan called Jeremy Silcox a dipshit.
[Elizabeth laughs]
- Wanna just go now?
- [Sophie] Yeah.
- Some of the songs are really hard.
- Mmm.
I've been listening to the recordings,
and she just… she sounds so good.
- And I just--
- Yeah, 'cause it's a recording.
You know, she had so many chances,
and she had so much time to figure it out.
You have time too, sweetie.
[Sophie sighs]
What?
- [retches]
- Mom!
- [Sophie] Oh…
- [Elizabeth gasps]
Oh, don't look, honey. Please don't look.
[coughing and gasping]
Oh! [gasps]
[breathing heavily]
[gentle, poignant music playing]
- [poignant music builds]
- [no in-scene audio]
[music continues]
[gentle music continues]
[Elizabeth] I know he said it's worse
and spreading faster
than he thought it would, but…
Can't be happening that fast, right?
Lizzie, I don't know.
Maybe the end of July or August?
He said he couldn't say.
I really… I don't think he knows.
I know he said, you know,
travel isn't a good idea,
but we can't not go to the beach house.
- Yeah.
- I already told Sophie.
Oh, God. And the show.
The show is so important to her.
[sighs]
Let's not tell them.
Just not yet.
Well, what about Soph?
- She'll quit the show.
- She's gonna want to know.
She has something that makes her happy,
and I can't let her lose that too.
They're gonna see what's happening.
Okay, we can tell them…
tell them that I'm struggling, but not…
And then, after the show,
we go to the Crane House.
- We'll all be together.
- Okay.
- And we can just tell them there.
- Great.
I think, in the meantime,
we can ask my parents to come help.
- Yeah. Whatever you want.
- Well, it's definitely not what I want.
- Uh… I know.
- But I just… think we're gonna need them.
But oh, my mom.
[sighs]
I'll take care of it.
Okay? I don't want you to worry.
I mean, I kind of need
something to worry about that's not…
that's not it.
Is… "it" your mom?
Or…
It's my mom? Uh, it's the…
- You… you said "it."
- It's the cancer.
- I got… I got con…
- [laughs]
I got confused.
[phone ringing]
- Hello?
- [Ted] Maybe I'm hopped up on coffee and…
[Elizabeth laughs]
Dad?
[Elizabeth] You thought I would say "it"?
You thought I would call her "it"?
- [laughing]
- [Ted] I won't tell anybody.
Especially it.
[Elizabeth and Ted laughing]
- [laughs]
- [Elizabeth] Yeah.
Oh my God.
- [laughing] Oh my God!
- [Ted] That's so cute.
[Elizabeth sighs]
- I'm sure I got the wrong cheese.
- I think the cheese is fine.
[Ethan] Mom, Mom, they're here!
- Doorbell doesn't work.
- It's this one, Grandpa Dale.
- [bell rings]
- Oh!
Joke never gets old, huh, Dale?
- Boys, quit it. Enough.
- Okay.
- When did you get so big?
- [Ted] Hug your grandmother, please.
Come over here, you!
Oh! Oh my goodness.
[Ted] All right, boys, inside. Let's go.
Oh!
- Excuse me, who is this woman?
- [laughs]
- Sophie, you're so gorgeous.
- Thank you.
- Oh, God. Where's your mother?
- She's right there.
- [grandmother] Oh, my baby.
- Hi, Mom.
[Caleb] Why are Grandpa Dale and Lala
staying in my room?
[Ted] Because you only
sleep in Ethan's room.
Yeah, but why do I have
to sleep on the trundle?
You literally refuse
to sleep anyplace else.
How long are they staying?
- [grandmother] Uh…
- Um, we don't know.
Yeah, and your mom said I might be able
to give you driving lessons?
Yeah, that'd be fun. Totally.
- Well, you guys must be starving.
- Come on, boys, let's go upstairs.
- Bring the bags.
- [Ethan] I wanna carry Grandpa's suitcase.
- [Caleb] No, I do! I do!
- [grandmother] Oh.
[Ted] Forget where the stairs are?
Oh. Oh. Well, uh…
I'm off creamy cheeses.
It's not good for my gut.
Oh.
[Dale] But, um…
I'll have a grape.
- Just a grape?
- [Dale] Yeah. Whoa.
Thank you.
Just one grape?
So after you come back
in the door, Sophie,
um, you grab him,
and that's where the kiss happens.
[whispers] Where's Carolyn?
Do you feel okay about that, Sophie?
Oh, uh… I don't know.
[Ms. Parker] Well, we can do something
other than a kiss. Like a hug or…
- Jack, what do you think?
- Oh, uh…
- I did a kiss last year. I'm cool.
- Yeah. I'm cool too, then.
Okay, great. So why don't we try one?
Okay.
[door slams loudly]
Sophie, you have to kiss him.
Yes.
[Ms. Parker] Good.
The thing is, right now, Jenna is thinking
she's made a huge mistake,
so maybe, mmm…
less smiley.
Oh.
Yeah. Um, sorry,
I was just trying an acting choice.
Yeah? Great.
- Do you wanna try it again?
- Yes.
["She Used to Be Mine" playing
through earbuds]
[grandmother] …Dale and I to come here
and say, "Let's straighten this out."
No, listen to me.
Our neighbor can get her into Dana-Farber.
Their cancer team
is top three in the country.
- [Ted] That's what all the hospitals say.
- [grandmother] They really are.
[Ted] Listen. We're doing
everything that we can.
We trust Dr. Steckman and his team.
- Who is Dr. Steckman? What hospital is--
- [Ted] You know him!
- [grandmother] I've never met the man.
- [Ted] The same doctor from last time!
- [buzz of conversation]
- [girl] Right. So, um…
I can't believe I missed you guys kissing.
I'm telling you,
the chemistry was undeniable.
Okay, remember when we made out
with those guys at camp,
and we were like, "Ew, it's so slimy,"
and we didn't get what the big deal was?
I get what the big deal is now. Like,
We were just kissing the wrong people.
Hey, Carolyn, you forgot this.
[Carolyn] Oh, thanks.
My legs are killing me from yesterday.
- You?
- Yesterday?
Yeah, we did this hike after school.
I thought it was gonna be like two miles,
and then it ended up
being four and a half miles.
Cool.
Yeah.
You should totally come with us next time.
Thank you, that's sweet.
You told me
you had a doctor's appointment.
I had to get a ride home
with Trista and her mom.
Wait, are you quitting the show?
I already did.
And you didn't tell me?
- I don't know. I didn't know how.
- I am so sorry.
- I didn't know. Yeah.
- It's okay. Can you just give us…
You have a lot going on, so I--
Yeah, you're right, I do have
a lot going on right now. I need to focus.
- Soph, I wanted to--
- Don't worry about driving me anymore.
My grandpa's just sitting around all day
with nothing to do. He loves to drive.
Sophie!
I need more practice.
Can we do extra rehearsals?
Mmm…
I'd rather devote my spare time
to lesson plans about Mesopotamia
and the spice trade routes
along the Tigris and Euphrates rivers.
Okay.
I'm kidding! That's so boring!
Yes, of course.
Oh, um, I shouldn't have said it's boring.
- Please don't tell Principal Howard.
- Yeah, of course not.
♪ It's a bad idea, me and you ♪
I know, I totally agree.
♪ I've never known anything so true ♪
♪ It's a terrible idea, me and you ♪
[Sophie] ♪ You have a wife ♪
[Jack] ♪ You have a husband ♪
- [Sophie] ♪ You're my doctor ♪
- [Jack] ♪ You've got a baby coming ♪
- [Sophie] ♪ It's a bad idea ♪
- [both] ♪ Me and you ♪
♪ Let's just keep kissing
Till we come to ♪
♪ Heart, stop racing, let's face it ♪
♪ Making mistakes like this ♪
♪ Will make worse
What was already pretty bad ♪
♪ Mind, stop runnin'
It's time we just let this thing go ♪
♪ It was a pretty good bad idea
Wasn't it, though? ♪
[all] ♪ I… ♪
- ♪ Da, dum, da, daa, da, dum, da, daa ♪
- ♪ I know it's right for me ♪
- ♪ It's the only thing ♪
- ♪ Da, dum, da, daa ♪
- ♪ I've ever done ♪
♪ Da, da, da ♪
- ♪ What if I never see myself ever be ♪
- ♪ Da, dum, da, daa, da, dum, da, daa ♪
♪ Anything more ♪
- ♪ Than what I've already become? ♪
- ♪ Da, dum, da, daa, da, da, da, da ♪
♪ Da, da, da ♪
- ♪ Da, da ♪
- [Sophie] ♪ I need a bad idea ♪
- ♪ Da, da, da, da ♪
- ♪ I need a bad idea ♪
- [Sophie and Jack] ♪ I need a bad idea ♪
- ♪ Da, da, da ♪
- ♪ I need a bad idea ♪
- ♪ Da, da, da, da ♪
- ♪ Just one ♪
♪ Heart, keep racing
Let's make mistakes ♪
♪ Let us say "So what?" ♪
♪ And make worse
What was already pretty bad ♪
♪ This secret is safe
No reason to throw it away ♪
♪ When there's love to be had ♪
♪ Hold me tight as I tell myself
That you might make sense ♪
♪ And make good
What has been just so bad ♪
♪ Let's see this through ♪
♪ It's a pretty good bad idea ♪
- [Jack] ♪ Me and you ♪
- [Sophie] ♪ Me and you ♪
[cheering and applause]
[Trista] Sophie! Sophie, good job!
[girl] Sophie, that was so good!
The band is sounding really great, guys.
- [girl] Yes!
- [laughter]
[Ms. Parker] Owen, what was the next note?
Oh, uh, to ask Fishman…
Oh! Fishman.
I want the diner windows to glow.
Word! I can build that.
Thank you, Fishman.
Okay. Um, uh…
Mallory. Uh…
Excellent. "When He Sees Me"
is gonna bring down the house.
You're very kind.
Um, Sophie.
You are doing such a good job.
I hope you feel that.
Uh… "She Used to Be Mine."
It's not quite there.
You are gonna get it.
Oh! Assignment!
Talk to your mom about what it was like
being pregnant with you.
I want your performance
to come from a place of truth.
Um…
Trista.
Yes, okay.
So, I noticed that pie customer three
was really angry today.
Yes, thank you.
My place of truth is that
the police are asking too many questions.
Okay.
[boy] See you later.
- Birenbaum.
- [girl 1] Catch you later.
Wanna run lines with me?
I still can't get the bus stop scene down.
- Oh. Now?
- Yeah.
My ride's here.
Oh. I can take you home after.
Okay. Hang on.
[girl 2] Thank you! You too!
You ready for today's lesson?
I noticed you didn't have any.
Uh, thanks, Grandpa Dale.
But would you mind
if I got a ride home with my friend?
Your friend is a young man
who's too handsome for his own good?
Yeah.
If I was your father, I'd say no.
But I'm your grandfather,
so I say wear a seat belt
and call me if he gets handsy.
We're just running lines.
Is that what they call it these days?
- [Sophie] Let's go. Yeah.
- Good?
- [car door slams]
- Let's go.
There's a plate in the fridge for Sophie.
Busy girl.
Yeah. She's really committed to it.
She's a very hard worker.
She gets that from me.
Are you sure you don't want me
to talk to her about what the doctor said?
Yeah, I'm sure, Mom.
Spaghetti sauce from Impellazari's.
[sighs] Do you think you could just
sit and read to me for a minute?
I love this book. I'm just so tired.
I will, if you finish that bowl.
What am I, six? Come on.
Just read. Just read.
- All right.
- [chuckles] Thank you.
- [dog barking]
- [Sophie] Thank you, doctor.
[Jack] Your hormones are
beautifully… progressing?
- [Sophie] No. Almost.
- Ugh! Damn, so am I like 50% right?
- At least 60.
- Still an F.
You're gonna get it. You were
the perfect Cinderella's prince last year.
You know it was my first show, right?
I basically auditioned 'cause
Ms. Parker would not stop bugging me.
- She heard I couldn't do track.
- You have plantar fasciitis.
Yeah.
Uh… my dad has that, so it sticks
in my head when other people do too.
Anyway, I should…
I was actually hoping
I could ask you something.
Yeah?
Do you think…
I don't know, maybe we could…
go easier on the kissing?
- Oh.
- In the show, I mean.
It's just, stage kisses don't usually
use tongue.
- Oh my God. I'm so sorry.
- No, it's just, you know…
- Adults are there. Elementary kids…
- All the times I hooked up with people?
- They're like, "Use more tongue."
- It's not like it's not good.
- Not "all the time."
- I…
Makes it sound like I'm making out
with everyone. I make out a normal amount.
Um…
I mean, I was gonna tell you your…
nose is always in a weird place, so…
I guess we could both work on things.
Anyway, thank you. Good night.
Good night.
[running footsteps]
Oh. [chuckles]
You okay?
Are you a good kisser?
Huh. Um, I mean, your dad says I am.
So did my college boyfriend. I guess…
I had a couple of good reviews.
[chuckles] Why?
Just asking.
What was it like to be pregnant with me?
Like, how did you feel?
Um…
Oh. Anxious.
Like, I was so scared
I was gonna eat the wrong thing, or…
Wait.
Why? Are you…
Yes.
[laughing] No. Of course not.
Oh my gosh. Okay.
Ms. Parker asked me to ask you.
She said it might be useful
for my performance.
Okay. Um…
Let me think of something useful.
Um, I…
I played a lot of Fleetwood Mac
around the house.
- 'Cause I wanted you to have good taste.
- Hmm.
- Well, that worked. I love Fleetwood Mac.
- You're welcome.
[gentle music playing]
Oh, and I was just nauseous all the time.
And then people were like,
"Oh, your baby's gonna have
a lot of hair."
- What?
- I know.
I was like, "That's so weird,
that my baby's hair
would make me wanna throw up."
But then, when you were born, you did.
You had this beautiful,
like, thick, dark hair.
[mouths]
[buzz of conversation]
[Ms. Parker] Hey, those of you in costume,
please be careful. We don't want stains.
[students gasping and laughing]
[Jack] Hey. Birenbaum.
- [door closes]
- Oh, I should…
Soph.
So, I know I said we should ease up a bit,
but I was thinking,
I don't know, maybe we could practice?
Just so we're on the same page.
Make sure my nose is in the right place
before we do it
in front of everyone again.
Wait, like, the kiss? Kissing practice?
That dress looks great on you, by the way.
It does?
[Ms. Parker] Okay, break's over!
We should…
So, was my nose okay?
Sophie! Jack!
Hey. Please don't leave your baby
in the middle of the stage. Okay, Sophie?
Sorry. Okay.
[light, optimistic music playing]
[Elizabeth] Sophie?
Look.
[Sophie] What's this?
It's my old maternity dress.
That's so sweet, Mom.
What if you wore it for the show?
'Cause Jenna wears one
for "She Used to Be Mine," right?
Oh, I already… have a dress.
Oh, totally.
I just… I don't decide the costumes.
- Ms. Parker's very particular.
- Yeah, of course you don't. Yeah.
- I'm sorry.
- Yeah, don't worry. Don't worry.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
- You sure you're okay?
- Yes. Yeah.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
[Ted] Hey, hey, I got dinner.
We're gonna eat outside.
Your children can't subsist
on leftover deli food.
Or… they can.
[grandmother] At least let me
get you some real dishes.
[Ted] Linda, we're fine.
We'll go with the paper plates.
[Ethan] Then we grab the sparklers
and go out to the sand,
and we wave them around
till it's all the way dark.
[Caleb] Sometimes Dad doesn't let me
have sparklers if I have too much candy.
- No.
- He's scared I'm gonna burn something.
Or someone.
[Dale] Lala doesn't let me have any sugar.
But that has more to do
with my tummy troubles.
[farting]
- Oh, Dad.
- Ooh!
- [boys] Ppht!
- Don't start.
- Ppht!
- [Dale] Like that. There you go.
Will you go again this year
to the beach house?
We always go. Right, Mom?
Yeah. Yeah.
Yes, of course.
Maybe you'll finish your book.
Linda, look at this.
The genius of paper plates.
Oh. Lovely.
- Can we talk about Mother's Day on Sunday?
- [Ethan] Mm-hmm.
All right. Thank you.
We do this beautiful thing at the deli.
It's a big buffet brunch.
And we have healthy options for you--
Ted. No one cares
about the healthy options.
- [Ethan] Yeah.
- Everybody care… You guys care.
- No, I'm not.
- Who said I'm on your side?
[Ted] Oh, oh! Okay, all right!
I can't remember the last time
we spent Mother's Day together.
- [Sophie] Wait, this Sunday?
- [Ted] Yeah.
I forgot to block it off. I'm supposed
to have rehearsal with Ms. Parker.
On a holiday weekend?
To be fair, I don't think anyone
considers Mother's Day a holiday weekend.
The show's next week, so…
Who does this on Mother's Day?
It's okay, Sophie. I get it.
[Sophie] Uh, I can cancel.
- [Ted] No, don't cancel. What time is it?
- It's supposed to be at 12:00.
- I could see about pushing it to 1:00.
- It's fine.
- You come for a bit.
- You're her father.
- You could tell her to skip the thing.
- [Ted] I appreciate it.
- But that's not how things work here.
- [scoffs]
Uh… I know you think
this play is very important.
- The cast is counting on me.
- It means a lot to her, Linda.
The cast is not as important--
- As Mom? Of course.
- [Ted] Linda!
Your mother wants to spend
Mother's Day with you!
- Linda, please.
- She's sick, Sophie! It's not right!
- Mom! That's enough.
- It's not right!
[poignant music playing]
Hey, uh…
I just, uh…
I just… [sighs]
You can let it out.
Not with me. I get it.
But you should with somebody.
[doorbell rings]
[Sophie sobbing]
[sighs]
I can't spend whatever…
[sighs] …time I have left
defending my choices.
She has to go.
You need me to do it?
Yeah.
Maybe things will feel better
in the morning. Maybe…
[sighs heavily]
Maybe they can stay for Mother's Day.
There's, like, years of shit
between parents and grandparents
that we're never gonna know.
I know, but they're, like,
super intense and mad.
It's better to stay out of it.
I know, but it's tough.
["Affection" by Between Friends
playing softly on speaker]
I'm sorry I didn't
tell you I quit the show.
[sighs] I'm sorry I didn't think
about how it'd feel for you.
No, it's okay. You've got enough going on.
No. I want to have room for you
no matter what.
[phone alert chimes]
[switches phone off]
You wanna see who it is?
What?
Oh.
Erin, um, says Spencer's cat-sitting
for his aunt. So he has the keys.
And other than three weird cats,
the place is empty.
Oh!
Do you…
Do you wanna go?
I don't know.
- Will there be alcohol?
- [giggles]
I hope.
["lemonade" by ekat19 playing]
- ♪ On that dash ♪
- ♪ On the road, I'm countin' stacks ♪
♪ Countin' stacks ♪
- ♪ That's why we livin' way too fast ♪
- I swear!
- ♪ We're too reckless, this shit a blast ♪
- [can opens]
♪ Girl, keep talking, get attached ♪
This shit is next-level.
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Said she crying, need a friend ♪
- ♪ Will you love me till the end? ♪
- ♪ Love me till the end ♪
- ♪ Fuck with me, I'm in my Benz ♪
- ♪ Fuck with me ♪
♪ Please don't make me make amends ♪
Ugh.
♪ Maybe you and I can find a way to make ♪
♪ Heroes, they know
Now she in my life a château ♪
♪ One thousand on the dash
I'm just hoping we don't crash now ♪
♪ Slow down, she won't
She just livin' way too fast now ♪
♪ I've been so gone
Baby, save me from ♪
["Not the Same"
by Tasha the Amazon playing]
♪ I'm not tryin'
To share it with the fakes ♪
♪ Sham friends don't get no champagne ♪
♪ Count the mouths before I cut the cake ♪
♪ I see you but we are not the same ♪
♪ I'm about the… that I came with ♪
- Yo, don't play any musical theater shit.
- [girl laughs]
All you theater kids
know how to do is that shit. Damn!
- [boy] Play some Kendrick.
- [girl] Yeah!
[plays glissando]
[vamping]
♪ You just gotta ♪
♪ Ignite the light ♪
♪ And let it shine ♪
♪ Just own the night ♪
♪ Like the 4th of July ♪
♪ 'Cause baby, you're a firework ♪
♪ Come on, show 'em what you're worth ♪
♪ Make 'em go ♪
[boy] What's up?
- [vomits]
- [all gasping]
[shocked laughter]
[Spencer] Dude, no!
My aunt is gonna kill me!
- [purring]
- [music thumping from next room]
[door opens]
Hey, Soph. Sophie, hi.
Hey, come on, we have to go.
- No, in a little bit.
- [cat yowling]
Uh, no, now. My mom just called.
Your dad is freaking out.
- Is it my mom?
- [Carolyn] No. No.
Um, I guess you were supposed
to be home by now.
- Shit. Shit, shit.
- [Carolyn] He's been calling.
He thinks you're at my house.
My mom's covering for us,
but he's on his way. We have to go.
Erin's sober.
I'll drive fast, but safe.
Come on. Let's go.
- Bye, kitty.
- [purring]
Ugh, who threw up in my bag?
You did. Let's go.
["Deceptacon" by Le Tigre playing]
[car lock bleeps]
♪ Every day and night ♪
- Do you want my driving gloves?
- [starts engine]
I'm good. Thanks.
♪ I can see your disco, disco dick
Is sucking my heart out of my mind ♪
♪ I'm outta time… ♪
He's not here yet. Thank you.
♪ I'm a gasoline gut
With a Vaseline mind, but ♪
♪ Wanna disco? Wanna see me disco? ♪
You're my hero.
- ♪ Let me hear you depoliticize my rhyme ♪
- Yes! Ow!
[whispers] Should I ring the doorbell?
♪ Who took the bomp
from the bomp-ah-lomp-ah-lomp? ♪
♪ Who took the ram
From the ram-ah-lam-ah-ding-dong? ♪
♪ Who took the bomp
from the bomp-ah-lomp-ah-lomp? ♪
- Ugh.
- [car pulling up]
[Carolyn] Soph, he's here!
He's here!
This is gonna be the greatest
acting challenge of your young life.
You know what time it is?
You're supposed to be home by 9:00.
Nine o'clock.
- Sorry. My phone was on silent.
- It was on silent. Okay.
Do you smell that?
What? No.
- [Ted] I'm not the reason she left Boston.
- [Linda] You think it was because of me?
- [Dale] Linda.
- [Ted] It's not about you.
[Dale] Ted, please. We'll go, okay?
- [Ted] I'm just trying to think about…
- [Linda] And I'm not?
[Dale] Thank you.
Good?
["Mama Said" by The Shirelles playing]
- [laughter]
- [Caleb] I want another donut.
[Ethan] Dad said no more donuts.
[Caleb] I just wanna lick it.
- [Ethan] Mom said you'll go home sick.
-Happy Mother's Day.
Seriously, guys.
- Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
- [Ethan] Dick!
Can you… Ethan!
- Dad said no more donuts.
- Yeah.
- Just worry about yourself, my honey.
- [Caleb babbling]
- [Elizabeth] Okay?
- [Caleb yells]
Mom, you okay?
- I am so sorry. Boys, can you apologize?
- You work here?
Um, yeah. I'm… I don't think we've met.
- I'm--
- Can I tell you something?
Our food was cold.
There's not enough healthy options.
We couldn't get anybody's attention,
and then your kid almost tackled my mom.
- I'm sorry. Is there a problem?
- Are you the dad?
- I got it, Ted.
- No, no.
- [man] Doesn't seem like you do.
- Can you not talk to my mom that way?
Why don't you leave?
Bill's on us. Happy Mother's Day.
Actually, you know what?
Just one sec before you go.
Why don't you take one of these
actually healthy kale wraps?
Or you know what?
Why don't you take all of the kale wraps?
Because we're not gonna do wraps anymore,
because we're a fucking deli.
- [claps and laughs]
- Yes!
[Elizabeth] All right.
[Ted] Come on, guys. Let's go.
- Mom!
- [Frank] Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- I got you!
- Dad!
- [Ted] Okay, okay. Stand up.
- [Sophie] Are you okay?
- [Caleb] Mom?
- [Ted] Stand up. It's okay. I got you.
- [Elizabeth whimpering]
- ♪ Mama said ♪
- ♪ Don't you worry ♪
- ♪ Mama said, Mama said, hey ♪
- [music fades]
[gentle, wistful music playing]
[Sophie] What did the doctor say?
[Elizabeth] I mean…
I'm pretty sick.
Yeah, I know that, but--
The doctor said we need to be careful.
But I don't get it.
Why can't we still go to the Crane House?
After what happened at the deli…
[sighs] …we're just gonna stay here.
Just the family.
Let your mom take it easy.
- This sucks.
- Ethan, enough already.
He's right. It sucks.
See?
Uh… also, Soph…
Your mom's not able to come to the show.
- What?
- [Ted] It's too much. It's too dangerous.
- She'd be around too many people.
- But do we still have to go?
- [Ted] Ethan.
- I'm so sorry, sweetheart.
I know they… they record the show, so…
Yeah, but it's not the same thing.
I know.
Um… maybe you can sing
some of your songs for me.
Here, like a living room performance.
- Soph, do you--
- [Sophie] It's fine, I understand.
Oh, buddy. Oh, hi.
Okay. Come here. Come here.
[power humming]
[sighs]
[Ms. Parker] Slower fade, please.
[Fishman yells] What?
A fade. A slower fade.
Oh, word! Word. All right.
I need to build that.
- Just give me a minute.
- [sighs]
[Ms. Parker] Okay, Fishman, you build.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah.
I just… I really wanted to do a good job
for someone, but they can't come.
A lot of other people will be here,
so you could do a good job for them.
- Yeah.
- [Ms. Parker] Or maybe just for you.
You know, I cast you because
I saw something in your callback.
And you've worked hard,
and it shows, but what I saw,
ooh, we can't work for that.
You either got it or you don't.
You got it, Birenbaum.
You just gotta remember where you put it.
Are you done?
What was it you said you wanted again?
[loud chatter]
[Ms. Parker] You'll lock up?
- [Owen] I'm on it.
- All right. Please get some rest, okay?
I want you to have lots of energy
for your dress rehearsal tomorrow.
- [Mr. Stewart] Good night.
- May the theater gods bless your sleep.
- [TJ] Yes, thank you, Ms. Parker.
- [Mallory] Good night.
[TJ] Appreciate you.
[Owen] Yeah, I'll lock up.
After tech night after hours!
[cheering]
["Tornado Warnings"
by Sabrina Carpenter playing]
[TJ] All right, all right, all right,
we all know the drill.
Phones in here, because tonight is sacred.
- So let's do it!
- [cheering]
♪ Our relationship arc ♪
♪ Ignoring tornado warnings ♪
- ♪ Don't understand how quickly we get ♪
- [TJ] Thanks, Sophie.
♪ Right back in our rhythm
Without missin' a step ♪
♪ And logically the last thing
I should have on my mind ♪
- ♪ But I want you there sometimes ♪
- [Sophie] No!
- We dug it.
- We--
♪ I guess maybe that's why ♪
♪ I'm lyin' to my therapist ♪
♪ I keep sayin' things like ♪
♪ "I never saw him and we never kissed" ♪
- In the name of Shakespeare…
- ♪ Sondheim ♪
- [TJ] And Lin-Manuel…
- [Owen] We all sign the wall.
Thus, all who come after us
shall know the glory that was…
[all yell] Waitress!
[cheering and whistling]
♪ To my therapist… ♪
Okay, come get your Sharpies!
I'm signing first.
- ♪ I deserve an hour in a week ♪
- [TJ] Yeah!
- ♪ To focus on my thoughts ♪
- [TJ] Yes!
♪ Not so obsessed with yours
I can't hear myself speak ♪
♪ I deserve my own consideration ♪
♪ Sometimes, I wish I kept ♪
♪ Some of my feelings in the basement ♪
♪ So I'd still have some left ♪
♪ Don't understand how quickly we get ♪
♪ Right back in our rhythm
Without missin' a step ♪
♪ And logically the last thing
I should have on my mind ♪
♪ But I want you there sometimes ♪
[TJ] So.
Who do we think's gonna hook up tonight?
[girl] Lots of possibilities.
Anything could happen.
Mike and Becca are already gone.
- Stop!
- Mike and…
- Really?
- [girl] I know!
- They just left the auditorium.
- [Jack] I'm gonna head to the bathroom.
Have fun.
Gonna have the time of my life.
Top ten bathroom experience?
Top five.
Think big, Birenbaum.
[soft, relaxed music playing]
- Just don't throw up on him. [laughs]
- Stop.
Go. Go, go.
[sighs]
[music fades]
"Hey, I had to go to the bathroom too.
Similar bladders!"
Ew, don't say the last part.
I have a boyfriend.
Right, from Stage Door Manor.
[Mallory] Don't say it like that.
It's very prestigious.
My boyfriend's a great actor.
Stage Door Manor? Absolutely!
So?
[Sophie] Mm-mm.
Oh.
Uh…
Oh, I don't know if you wanna go back in.
Uh, it turned into a make-out den.
Trista's eating Fishman's face.
- Yeah, sounds messy.
- Mmm.
At least you get a stage kiss.
I give my life to this program every year.
I've never even gotten
to fake kiss anyone.
[Sophie sighs]
- No.
- No. [chuckles]
[Sophie] Thank you.
[Jack] Birenbaum.
Need a ride?
- Thank you.
- [chuckles]
Are you nervous for tomorrow?
'Cause I'm so nervous.
I didn't know you get nervous.
I still feel like
I'm not fully off book yet.
You're gonna be great, Jack.
You're always great.
Are we practicing again?
You were just kissing Mallory.
I… I thought you liked me.
I'm starting to think you only
do the plays to kiss all the girls,
which is honestly kind of sad.
I'm done kissing the wrong guys.
Let's not let this affect the show, okay?
[starts engine]
[phone plays sound of rooster crowing]
When do you think
they'll announce next year's show?
- Probably tonight.
- [Mallory trills]
- [laughing] Tonight?
- [trills] Ahem.
- [Sophie singing]
- [sliding] Ma! Ma!
- [Sophie humming]
Ma! Ahem.
[Mallory trills]
- [piano playing]
- [boy] Left… No…
[Ms. Parker] Hi, Mrs. Birenbaum.
- Hi.
- [girl] What's the time?
Hey, thank you so much
for letting me watch.
I am so glad you reached out.
And she's not gonna know, right?
No. No.
Thank you for… everything
that you've been doing with Sophie.
It's been so amazing
to see her working so hard.
TJ, you are so late. Get backstage.
Sorry, my Yoo-hoo exploded in my backpack.
- I don't care. Go!
- [TJ] Okay, I'm going! Okay.
[Fishman] Bro, double-check the levels.
[boy 1] Okay, checking…
- Uh…
- [boy 1] Sounds good.
- She is amazing.
- Yeah.
I had no idea things were so…
[cast] One, two, three!
One, two, three! One, two, three!
One, two! One, two! One, two! One, two!
One! One! One! One!
[whooping and cheering]
- [Mr. Stewart] Okay.
- All right.
Give it your all, okay?
I know it's just a dress rehearsal,
but you never know if a Broadway
casting director might be watching.
[all] Ooh!
[boy] Hey, Broadway! Hey, Broadway!
[cast chattering]
[Mallory] Where is everybody?
Get to your sides, everybody!
Hey, what time…
Get to your sides. All right?
[girl 1] ♪ Sugar ♪
♪ Sugar ♪
♪ Sugar, butter, sugar, butter ♪
- ♪ Sugar, butter ♪
- [girl 2] ♪ Flour ♪
- ♪ Flour ♪
- ♪ Sugar, butter ♪
♪ My hands pluck the things
I know that I'll need ♪
- ♪ Flour ♪
- ♪ I take the sugar and butter ♪
- ♪ From the pantry ♪
- ♪ Sugar, butter ♪
♪ I add the flour to begin
What I'm hoping to start ♪
♪ And then it's down with the recipe
And bake from the heart ♪
- ♪ Sugar ♪
- ♪ Ooh, ooh, sugar, butter ♪
- ♪ And butter ♪
- ♪ Sugar, butter ♪
- ♪ And flour ♪
- [boy] Oh!
- [Mallory squeals]
[gasps]
[Ms. Parker] Everybody okay?
Hey, sorry!
- You good, Sophie?
- [Sophie] Yeah. We're good. Thank you.
Okay, so let's just take a minute
and take care of that, please.
[Owen] One more time. Clean it up.
- This run-through sucks.
- Bad run-through means great show.
- Did you see the computer and camera?
- Is Ms. Parker, like, live streaming it?
I heard someone's watching
from their couch.
- Weird.
- Who do you think it is?
Isn't it obvious?
A Broadway casting director.
- [laughter]
- Could you imagine?
"What Baking Can Do" was, um…
really emotionally resonant today.
- [knock at door]
- Back in two minutes, people. Back in two.
Thank you, two.
You're doing a good job.
- [knocking]
- [Jack] Sophie.
Yeah.
You ready for act two? We're good, right?
I just wanted to say,
uh, I'm so sorry.
I heard your mom's really sick.
TJ said that he saw
your mom talking to Ms. Parker.
My… my parents got divorced
a few years ago. Um…
I'm not saying it's the same.
Um, it's not, but…
Just… let me know
if I can be there for you, okay?
We wouldn't have sucked so bad
if we'd known she was watching.
[Trista] I'm really sorry, Sophie.
[Fishman] Lights up.
Sorry, it's a little messy,
but Sophie's doing so great.
- No, thank you, it's wonderful.
- [Fishman] Ms. Parker?
Carl is locked
in the spotlight booth again.
[Ms. Parker] What? Ugh!
- I told you to give him the keys.
- [Fishman] I didn't think it'd happen ag--
[piano playing "She Used To Be Mine"]
- [Sophie] ♪ It's not simple to say ♪
- Shoot.
- Oh.
- ♪ That most days ♪
- [Elizabeth] Ted!
- [Sophie] ♪ I… ♪
[Elizabeth] Ted!
Hey, Ted?
- [sobbing]
- [Ted] Hey, hey, hey.
What's going on? What's… what's wrong?
What?
[sobbing]
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
It's okay, Sophie.
- It's okay.
- I'm so sorry.
- No, I'm sorry. And you're doing great.
- No, I…
- Hey! You are doing great, okay?
- [sniffles]
Why don't you go home, huh?
- [whimpers]
- And come back fresh tomorrow for opening.
- Okay.
- Okay?
I wish you didn't do that.
- I just wanted to see you. I'm sorry.
- Mom, you should've asked me!
I… I didn't want to get your hopes up.
- In case I was feeling too sick.
- You can talk to me! I'm not a little kid!
I know. I know that.
You're growing up so fast.
- I feel like I'm… missing so much--
- Mom, you told me to do the show!
I did, yes, and of course
you should have done the show.
But I didn't know you were…
[sobs]
- You didn't tell me.
- I wanted to fight it.
I wanted to fight it,
and I tried so hard. I've been trying.
If you had told me, I wouldn't have
worked so much on the show.
You were so excited about it, honey.
I didn't want to ruin it for you.
You should have let me choose!
- You're right.
- I asked for extra rehearsals.
- Oh, honey.
- I'm not good enough.
- And I didn't wanna be around here.
- You're great.
- And me and Carolyn have been so weird.
- What happened with Carolyn?
- And now everything's awful.
- Honey.
Honey, I know things are hard. I know.
But… but, please…
You… you're so wonderful.
- Mom, do not lie about that too.
- I'm not lying!
- I'm not lying.
- Yes, you are! It's terrible! I'm terrible!
- No. No, no, no. Honey, no.
- [sobbing]
Listen to me.
Sophie, just look at me, okay?
I'm so sorry I didn't tell you.
I don't know how to do this.
- Mom, just…
- It's hard.
Just say it.
[sighs]
- Sophie.
- Say it.
[sighs]
I'm not gonna make it.
[sobbing] No, no, no.
No.
[Elizabeth] Hey.
[sniffles]
[sobbing]
- [sighs]
- [footsteps going upstairs]
[sighs]
[emotional, somber music playing]
[birdsong]
[whispers] Can you wake up, please? Buddy.
Wake up.
Hi, how'd you sleep? Good morning.
- [Sophie] Bye. Love you.
- [Caleb] Bye, Sophie. Bye, Dad.
You good? You've got everything? Goodbye.
[school bell rings][sighs heavily]
You okay?
No.
Are you?
[sighs heavily]
No.
Soph, everything that's happening
is so unfair.
It's unfair for you, for me,
for your brothers, for Mom.
- [sniffles]
- Yeah.
I know all she's trying to do
is make it hurt less, but I don't…
I don't think that's possible.
[sniffles]
And I so wish we could just fast-forward
to the part where you forgive us, but…
I know that's not possible either.
I hate you're going through this,
because every time I look at you,
all I see is how much I love you.
It's what Mom sees too.
[music fades]
[Carolyn] I'm with you for all of it.
No matter what, okay?
Also, I got you something.
[laughs]
I know I'm not in the play, but it doesn't
mean that all the traditions have to end.
It's really cute. Thank you.
- To a good show.
- Mmm!
- Mmm! [laughs]
Uh, and Sophie,
me and Erin are so excited to see you.
And we're, uh…
I know. The chemistry is undeniable.
[chuckles]
At least one of us
is kissing the right person.
- Come here.
- [laughs]
[upbeat, warm music playing]
- [Carolyn] So cute!
- [Sophie] I know, right?
[Ms. Parker] Thanks, guys.
- [Mr. Stewart] You ready for tonight?
- [Ms. Parker] Hey, guys.
- [Mr. Stewart] Come in. It's time.
- [boy 1] Yeah!
- [girl 1] Yeah, I'm sure you did.
- [girl 2] How many?
- [phone alert chimes]
- [boy] All right, let's do it.
You can play Jenna, right?
And Audrey knows Dawn?
Excuse me?
I'm sorry, I have to go.
You'll be better than me anyway.
I'll be amazing.
[tires screech]
- Thank you, TJ.
- Love you, Soph.
- [door slams]
- [Sophie] Mom?
[sniffles]
I'm really scared.
Me too.
I'm so sorry, sweetheart.
But if we're both scared,
who's gonna take care of us?
Your hot chauffeur husband.
[laughs]
Well, what if there is
no hot chauffeur husband?
Then I guess we'll have
to take care of ourselves.
- Women's rights.
- [laughs]
Wait. Shouldn't you be getting
into costume right now?
I don't want to miss
another minute with you.
[Elizabeth] Oh…
Oh, honey, no.
[sighs]
Your second-grade concert…
You cried so much. You were so proud.
I know.
No, wait. Wait. [sniffles]
I had looked for years
for a thing that lit me up.
And you found it by seven.
I cried because I thought,
no matter what,
you could return to that light
and you'd be okay.
But I don't wanna do the show without you.
I don't wanna do any of it without you.
You're never gonna be without me.
[sniffles]
I'm sorry you never found
the thing that lit you up.
But I did. [sniffles]
[band tuning up]
[Ted] Right here, this is us. This is us.
All the way in. All the way in. Okay,
- Whee! Whoo!
- [Ted sighs heavily]
- Whoo!
- [seat squeaking]
[outgoing call ringing]
[ringing]
Elizabeth?
You should be in Sophie's life.
You should be in all of their lives.
I… just need you to listen to her.
[gasps]
Uh… I will. I promise I will.
- Okay?
- [sighs]
I love you so much, Elizabeth.
[sobs] I love you too, Mom.
You can tell her stories about me?
You have all the stories.
- I know that this is last-minute.
- [mouths]
I'm sorry, but…
I know it would mean a lot to her
if you could
make it to closing night
of her show tomorrow.
[Linda] Um…
Is tonight okay instead?
[chuckles]
Of course, you're there already.
No, well, I'm sorry. Your father
said we shouldn't, but I insisted.
[Elizabeth chuckles]
- [car horn blares]
- [tires squeal]
- [man] Hey, hey!
- [Sophie] Oh, I'm sorry! No, no! Oh, no!
Oh my God.
[car lock bleeps]
- I'm so sorry, but--
- [Mallory] Don't worry.
I stalled.
I knew you'd come back.
And, um…
I like playing Dawn better anyway.
[chuckles]
- Are you wearing driving gloves?
- What? No.
[applause]
[girl] You're gonna do great, Sophie.
Hey, Sophie.
- I like your dress.
- Thank you.
[piano playing "She Used to Be Mine"]
♪ It's not simple to say ♪
♪ That most days I don't recognize me ♪
♪ That these shoes and this apron
That place and its patrons ♪
♪ Have taken more than I gave them ♪
♪ It's not easy to know ♪
♪ I'm not anything like I used to be ♪
♪ Although it's true I was never ♪
♪ Attention's sweet center ♪
♪ I still remember that girl ♪
♪ She's imperfect, but she tries ♪
♪ She is good, but she lies ♪
♪ She is hard on herself ♪
♪ She is broken and won't ask for help ♪
♪ She is messy, but she's kind ♪
♪ She is lonely most of the time ♪
♪ She is all of this mixed up ♪
♪ And baked in a beautiful pie ♪
♪ She is gone, but she used to be ♪
♪ Mine ♪
♪ It's not what I asked for ♪
♪ Sometimes life ♪
♪ Just slips in through a back door ♪
♪ And carves out a person ♪
♪ And makes you believe it's all true ♪
♪ And now I've got you ♪
♪ You're not what I asked for ♪
♪ If I'm honest
I know I would give it all back ♪
♪ For a chance to start over ♪
♪ And rewrite an ending or two ♪
♪ For that girl that I knew ♪
♪ Who was reckless just enough ♪
♪ Who gets hurt ♪
♪ But who learns how to toughen up ♪
♪ When she's bruised ♪
♪ And gets used by a man who can't love ♪
♪ And then she'll get stuck
And be scared ♪
♪ Of the life that's inside her
Growing stronger each day ♪
♪ Till it finally reminds her
To fight just a little ♪
♪ To bring back the fire in her eyes ♪
♪ That's been gone but used to be ♪
♪ Mine ♪
♪ Oh, used to be ♪
♪ She is messy ♪
♪ But she's kind ♪
♪ She is lonely most of the time ♪
♪ She is all of this mixed up ♪
♪ And baked in a beautiful pie ♪
♪ She is gone ♪
♪ But she used to be ♪
♪ Mine ♪
[clapping]
[crickets chirping]
[crickets continue chirping]
["Silver Springs"
by Fleetwood Mac playing]
♪ You could be my silver spring ♪
♪ Blue green, colors flashin' ♪
♪ I would be your only dream ♪
♪ Your shinin' autumn ♪
♪ Ocean crashin' ♪
♪ And don't say that she's pretty ♪
♪ And did you say that she loved you ♪
♪ Baby, I don't wanna know ♪
♪ So I'll begin not to love you ♪
♪ Turn around, see me runnin' ♪
♪ I'll say I loved you years ago ♪
♪ Tell myself you never loved me ♪
♪ No ♪
♪ And don't say that she's pretty ♪
♪ And did you say that she loved you ♪
♪ Baby, I don't wanna know ♪
♪ Oh, no ♪
♪ And can you tell me, was it worth it? ♪
♪ Baby, I don't wanna know ♪
♪ Time casts a spell on you ♪
♪ But you won't forget me ♪
♪ I know I could have loved you ♪
♪ But you would not let me ♪
♪ Time casts a spell on you ♪
♪ But you won't forget me ♪
♪ I know I could have loved you ♪
♪ But you would not let me ♪
♪ Well, I'll follow you down ♪
♪ Till the sound of my voice
Will haunt you ♪
♪ Give me just a chance ♪
♪ You'll never get away ♪
♪ From the sound
Of the woman that loves you ♪
♪ Was I just a fool? ♪
♪ I'll follow you down ♪
♪ Till the sound of my voice
Will haunt you ♪
♪ Give me just a chance ♪
♪ You'll never get away ♪
♪ From the sound
of the woman that loves you ♪
♪ Time casts a spell on you ♪
♪ But you won't forget me ♪
♪ I know I could have loved you ♪
♪ But you would not let me ♪
♪ I'll follow you down till the sound ♪
[song fades]
[bright, upbeat
instrumental music playing]
[music fades]
[warm, optimistic
instrumental music playing]
[music fades]